Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Science, Technology, and Society, Honors Theses SC4-3441 SC4-3441
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in Science, Technology, and Society, honors theses
1990-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Program in Science, Technology, and Society
SC4-3441
1 Linear Feet (24 volumes in 3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in Science, Technology, and Society at Stanford University.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in Science, Technology, and Society at Stanford University.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Technology -- Social aspects -- Study and teaching; Science -- Social aspects -- Study and teaching; Student papers.; Stanford University. Program in Science, Technology, and Society
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Anderson, Erin, Bicycles for South African women: a case study of cross-cultural technology transfer., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Bobulsky, Susan C., Holes in the safety net: how information technology is shaping health care and pharmaceutical access for California's medically indigent., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Gachiengo, Patricia Wambui, Appropriate technological innovation: a case study of the Jua Kali manufacturing sector in Kenya., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Granberg, Leif, The empathy machine: how felt experience shapes user understanding of kinetic machines., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Irani, Lilly, A different voice: women exploring Stanford computer science., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Jennifer, "It's not the end of the world:" agency and identity in historical (con)texts., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Lombera, Sofia, The international dimensions of neuroethics: the development of a new field of inquiry., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Luu, Vu, Children and computer networks: analysis and socio-technical provisions for the debate between children's safety and free speech., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Moon, Gina, Intellectual property protection for traditional knowledge: the case of the Hoodia Gordonia., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Nelson, Andrew J., Semaphore societies: the role of culture in the development of 19th-century British and American railroad signaling., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Rodriguez, Diego A., Design, craftsmanship, and the Ferrari aesthetic., 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fournier, Rachel Thoennes, Alchemical forces behind the scientific revolution: the paracelsian influence on early modern science., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kraus, Ali, Computer training and the empowerment of welfare mothers., 2001 (Box 2)
  - Putnam, Michael J., Computerization, human rights advocacy and organizational change: a case-study of the Czech Helsinki Committee., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Ratan, Rabindra (Robby) Ayyan, The evolution of rap and roll: an analysis of rap music's technological relationships, cultural connections, and historical trends., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Trope, Lee, Preventing cervical cancer: stakeholder attitudes toward FastHPV-focused screening programs in Roi-Et Province, Thailand., 2008 (Box 2)
  - Toy, Edmond, A political science: scientific and engineering expertise in Congress., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Sun, Edward Tai, Scaling the wall: West German television spillover and the collapse of communism in East Germany., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Terrell, Colleen, Building a new center: technology and the contemporary value dialectic., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Chng, Hak Peng, Energy in China: the crisis of history., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Jani, Navin P. M., The philosophical ramifications of new money., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chabot, Christian N., Techno-paradigm shift in the U.S. high technology industry: analyzing innovation, organization and competition., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Krauss, Steven, Electronic democracy: promises, prospects, and problems and its potential for development at Dartmouth College., 1991 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Crichton, Danny, "Academic revolution and regional innovation: the case of computer science at Stanford", 2011 May 17 (Box 1)